Tenkai... I killed you back then.
天海…当年我已经把你杀了
You were banished from this world.
你早就被驱逐出这个世界了
I will finish you once again.
我不介意再一次了结你
Then I'll banish you for eternity.
而我会将你永远驱逐出去
What's going on?
这是怎么回事？
My flowers!
我的花！
This accursed place...
是这个被诅咒之地…
It's surprising it still exists.
没想到它屹立至今
This place is a testament to our resolve.
此地见证了我们的决心
It's a perfect place to banish you.
在这里驱逐你再完美不过
It's clear that you bonded with a foolish human.
显然 和你缔结契约的 是一个愚蠢的人类
How, in the shadows?
你怎么能进入阴影？
Tomori. It was a thoughtful gesture from the Five Spears.
拓莫离 这是“五矛”组织赠予我的贴心礼物
It has the Yokai power seized from your brethren.
其中蕴含从你的同族身上 夺取的妖力
Can you hear it?
你能听到吗？
The pitiful cries of the decaying Yokai as their power is drained away.
腐烂的妖怪在自己的妖力被夺走时 发出的惨叫声
Good grief.
真是可惜
Izzy. Welcome back.
伊姬 欢迎回来
Are you still mad?
你还在生我的气吗？
About the whole "banishing you" thing.
因为我们想“驱逐你”的事
Something stinks!
有什么臭味！
Sorry!
抱歉！
We are a couple, right?
我们是情侣 对吧？
How about we establish some rules for our future
不如我们为未来的日子约法三章
so that we can maintain a good relationship?
以帮助我们 维持良好的关系 怎么样？
Says the one who tried to banish me with a spell.
试图用咒语驱逐我的人 竟然有脸说这种话
Sorry.
对不起
You must be tired today.
今天你一定已经很累了
I have to study for tomorrow's test,
我要为明天的考试复习
so you can use the bed to rest.
所以你可以睡在床上好好休息
Good night.
晚安
Come on, hitchhiking at this hour?
拜托 你怎么在这个时间搭便车？
I need this vehicle.
我需要这辆车
What?
啊？
Oh, well.
好吧
I was just thinking I could use someone to talk to.
我正想有人陪我聊聊天呢
Lucky for both of us.
我们俩都挺走运的
Hop in.
上车吧
Cool car, right?
这车很酷吧？
-It's strange. -So are you.
-很奇怪 -你也很奇怪
I've been traveling around in this car for various adventures.
我一直开着这辆车四处旅行 寻求多姿多彩的冒险
Are you a monk?
你是和尚吗？
The last time I was called to this world was in 1979.
上次有人这么称呼我还是1979年
Being a monk really means being isolated from the world.
看来当和尚确实与世隔绝啊
So, what were you doing in a place like this?
那你来这种地方做什么？
My only goal
我唯一的目标
is to eliminate
就是将那个可悲的蠢货
that wretched fool from this world.
驱逐出这个世界
Sounds tough.
听起来并非易事
Are you single?
你是单身吗？
Got any friends you can talk to?
有什么可以和你聊天的朋友吗？
All my friends are dead.
我的朋友全都死了
Well, cheer up. Life has its ups and downs.
别太难过 人生就是有起有伏的
If you need a friend, I'm here.
如果你需要朋友 我随时奉陪
Friend...
朋友…
If you ever run into trouble, I'll have your back, pal!
如果你遇到麻烦 我会罩着你 朋友！
Not a bad idea.
这主意不错
Izzy.
伊姬
Here.
给你
-What's this? -You have a test today.
-为什么做这个？ -你今天要考试
Eat this and ace it.
吃掉这个 考试拿高分
Bed hair.
头发都睡乱了
Stop.
别弄了
You look sleepy. Are you all right?
你看起来很困 没事吧？
Seems like he had a busy night.
看来他这一晚很忙呢
What?
嗯？
Check the sound when watching porn.
拜托你看黄片的时候音量放小点
Language.
怎么说话呢
But...
可是…
Do you know a kid named Hayato Ippongi?
你认不认识 一个叫一本木隼人的孩子？
Sorry, I don't really know.
抱歉 我不认识他
TADASHI INUKAI
犬饲忠士
Shoot, I gotta get going.
糟糕 我得赶紧出发了
I'll eat later. Thanks for the meal.
我待会再吃 谢谢您做的饭
I hope she's not here.
她没跟来吧
Calm down and act normal.
冷静 表现得正常点
What's the status?
现在是什么状况？
I'm thinking of finding a way to coexist with her.
我在思考一种能和她共存的办法
A Yokai that decapitates people?
和砍人脑袋的妖怪共存？
It might work if we find some ground rules for us.
如果我们设立一些基础规则 也许就能实现共存
Are you serious?
你是认真的吗？
I want to resolve this situation without hurting anyone.
我想在不伤害任何人的前提下 解决目前的困境
And that takes time, you know?
这需要时间 你懂吗？
Hachi. By any chance, have you
八公 你不会是
seriously fallen in love with her?
真的爱上她了吧？
-In love? -Have you?
-爱上？ -是不是？
Have I...
我是不是…
Yes.
是
Oh, my God.
我的天啊
You're completely into her.
你完全迷上她了
Can you handle her?
你能控制住她吗？
It's okay. I'll make sure she follows the rules.
没关系的 我会确保她遵守我们的规则
Let's just focus on taking the exam fair and square.
我们先专注于考试吧 正大光明地用实力去考
-All right!
-好！
I have awakened.
我被唤醒了
Escaping from the deadly god Izanami, I have returned to this world...
我逃离死神伊邪那美的魔爪 回到了人世间…
Wait.
等等
You killed me.
是你杀了我
And brought you back to life.
也是我将你起死回生
No. You stabbed me, and...
不 你捅了我 然后…
Then...
然后…
What is this?
这是怎么回事？
You have become the living dead. Just like me.
你成为了活死人 就像我这般
I don't want this!
我不要！
Stop messing with me.
别开玩笑了
Bring me back to where I belong.
把我送回我该待的地方
Your fate is now in my hands.
如今你的命运由我掌控
What do you want from me?
你想要我做什么？
TO IZZY - HELP YOURSELF.
写给伊姬 请享用
AND DON'T GET FOUND BY MY FAMILY! HACHI
还有 千万别被我家人发现！ 八公留
Completely flunked the course.
我肯定要挂科了
Same here.
我也是
Our grades keep dropping endlessly.
我们的成绩一直在无休止地下降
At this rate, we can't get a job anywhere.
照这样下去 我们去哪都找不到工作
Or worse, we might get killed by a Yokai.
或者更糟 我们可能被妖怪杀死
Look.
你看
Hey, Big Sweat... Like father, like son.
喂 “汗仔”… 真是有其父必有其子啊
What do you mean?
你这是什么意思？
Are you kidding me?
你在开玩笑吗？
Because of your old man's incompetence in the police,
就是因为你那个警察老爹的无能
Hayato's killer is still at large.
杀害隼人的凶手至今还在逍遥法外
Well... I'm really sorry about what happened to your cousin.
这个…你的表亲遭遇了那种事 我真的深表遗憾
My condolences...
请节哀…
-Izzy. -Let me go.
-伊姬 -放开我
It hurts!
好疼！
Izzy. It's okay now.
伊姬 现在没事了
Masato... I'm sorry for everything.
正人…不管怎样 真的对不起
Shut up.
你闭嘴
Someday I'll definitely settle the score.
改天我一定会找你算账
So don't you run away!
所以你休想逃跑！
It looks like that idiot is the one running away.
看起来逃跑的分明是那个蠢货
Well, why are you here?
你怎么来了？
I came to thank you for the food.
我来感谢你给我的食物
The omelet?
煎蛋卷吗？
I loved that.
我很喜欢
Please, just disappear from our lives.
求你了 从我们的生活中消失吧
Do you want me to skewer your skull and turn your skin inside out?
你是不是想让我一刀插进你的头骨里 把你的皮全部翻过来？
It's okay.
没事 别怕
Izzy?
伊姬？
Are you all right?
你没事吧？
Anyway, let's go.
不管怎样 我们先离开这儿
Goodbye.
拜拜
Forever.
永别了
I'm sorry.
对不起
Damn her sharp hearing.
她的听力真是该死的敏锐
Hey, it's Koki!
嘿 是科希
What are you doing?
你在干什么呢？
You went missing, and there's a big fuss about it.
你失踪后 事情闹得很大
Rumors say that you're involved
有传言说你参与了
in some shady business online and you're on the run.
网络上一些不正当的生意 逃亡去了
Hey, that's creepy!
喂 这太诡异了！
ROKUBANCHO UNIVERSITY STUDENT MURDER CASE
六畔町大学生杀人案
VICTIM: HAYATO IPPONGI CASE OVERVIEW
受害者：一本木隼人 - 案件概要
IPPONGI CONSTRUCTION COMPANY
一本木建设公司
I called Ippongi Construction, Hayato's father's company
我给隼人父亲的公司 一本木建设
five times to make an appointment, but no response.
打了五个电话预约会面 但至今没得到任何回复
While waiting for a call back,
在等待对方回电的时候
I've mastered the dance that's gone viral
我学会了最近在照片墙快拍上
on Instagram Stories lately.
非常流行的舞
If you're going to dance, do it at home.
如果你想跳舞 就回家跳
Isn't it odd, though?
可这不是很奇怪吗？
His son's head was cut off, which has gone missing,
他儿子的脑袋被砍掉 至今不知所踪
yet he ignores calls from the police.
而他却完全不接警方打过去的电话
Ippongi Construction evolved
一本木建设是从大约500年前
from a family of carpenters in Nara about 500 years ago.
一个奈良的木匠世家发展至今的
It's the largest in the industry,
如今它是业内规模最大的公司
with a total of 250,000 employees including related companies.
加上各类相关公司 共拥有25万名员工
Hayato's father, Takeru Ippongi, is the president of this massive company.
隼人的父亲一本木武尊 目前是这家巨型企业的社长
Let's go to Ippongi.
我们去一本木建设走一趟
Are we raiding them?
我们要去突袭吗？
Don't you dare dance in the president's office.
你可千万别在社长办公室起舞
I'm back. Here.
我回来了 给你
Try this.
尝尝这个
Did you get a headache?
冻得头疼了吧？
It's cold, so eat slowly.
它很冰 你要慢慢吃
So, Izzy...
对了 伊姬…
I've made notes in my Notes app about our rules and agreements.
我用“笔记”软件草拟了 几条我们之间的规则和协议
Rule one, about the house.
规则一 关于房子的事
We need a place for you to live.
我们得找个地方给你住
I live with you, and all my belongings are there.
我和你住在一起 我的全部家当都在你的房间
That's the problem.
问题就在于此
Having weapons and a severed head in my room is not good.
把武器和人头放在我的房间 太不妙了
Don't worry.
别担心
I stored the weapons under the bed.
我已经把武器藏到床底下了
That's the worst!
那是最糟的！
Mothers always want to search under their son's bed.
全世界的老妈都喜欢翻儿子的床底
Besides, you want a space for yourself, right?
再说了 你也想要 属于自己的空间 对吧？
Rule two, fit into this world.
规则二 融入这个世界
You need to be less conspicuous.
你得尽量别这么惹人注目
Like your clothes.
比如你的着装
Is my appearance a problem?
我的外表不行吗？
It's not a complaint, but the whole vibe...
我不是说我不喜欢 但是你的整个气场…
This is valuable armor made from the skin of Uwabami serpent.
这是用宇羽波美巨蛇的皮 制成的宝贵盔甲
Is that popular in your world?
这种衣服在你的世界很流行吗？
It fits in this world, too.
这套衣服在这个世界也不违和
You're looking great. One more, please.
你看起来超美 再来一张 拜托了
Okay, let's discuss the clothing later.
好吧 那我们待会再讨论着装的问题
Next is the last rule.
接下来是最后一条规则
The third rule is the most important.
第三条规则是最重要的
Rule three, do not kill anyone.
规则三 不许杀任何人
No, that's necessary.
不行 这是必要之举
To kill people?
杀人吗？
No matter the reason, it's wrong to kill anyone.
无论是出于什么理由 杀人就是不对
Izzy?
伊姬？
Are you all right?
你还好吗？
Are you in pain?
你很痛吗？
Is there any pure spring water somewhere?
哪里有纯净的泉水？
Spring water?
泉水？
Izzy? Izzy!
伊姬？伊姬！
Good, you're awake.
太好了 你醒了
Izzy, it's spring water.
伊姬 这是泉水
Amazing.
好神奇
This sacred spring holds mysterious power.
这里的神圣泉水蕴含着神秘的魔力
This place?
这里吗？
Where are we?
我们这是在哪儿？
Behind the temple nearby.
在附近一家寺庙的后面
Why did you bring me here?
你为什么带我来这儿？
When I was a kid, my grandma brought me here.
小时候 我奶奶带我来过这里
It's the only place that comes to mind for clean water.
提到干净的水 这是我唯一能想到的地方
It's strange.
好奇怪啊
You really understand me well.
你真的很懂我
Wow.
天啊
Beautiful.
真美
Yeah.
是啊
Hey.
嘿
Why didn't you tell me about your injury?
你怎么没跟我说你受伤了？
Showing weakness would be the end.
一旦表现出脆弱 我就完了
We're lovers, aren't we?
可我们是情侣 不是吗？
I can't trust the human world.
我无法信任人类世界
Even if you can't trust the human world,
就算你没法相信人类世界
trust me.
但你可以相信我
IPPONGI CONSTRUCTION COMPANY
一本木建设公司
Quit looking around.
别再东张西望了
It's my first time visiting a billionaire or a conglomerate.
这是我第一次来见亿万富翁 也是第一次参观企业集团
It's a self-indulgent show of an inherited conglomerate.
这只是一个继承制的企业集团 为炫耀自己的自导自演罢了
You follow the trend, too?
你也这么紧跟潮流？
We'd like to see Mr. Takeru Ippongi.
我们想见见一本木武尊先生
Sorry for the sudden visit.
抱歉突然来访
I'm Detective Inukai from the Investigation Division...
我是刑侦科的犬饲警探
What do you see?
你从中看到了什么？
I would like to inquire about your son, if I may.
您不介意的话 我想就令郎的事问您几个问题
A dolphin? Or maybe a raccoon?
是海豚？还是一只浣熊？
Mr. Ippongi?
一本木先生？
Sometimes you need to change your perspective
有时你需要改变观察视角
to see things correctly.
才能看到事物真正的样貌
What do you see?
你从中看到了什么？
-A dinosaur. -Interesting.
-一只恐龙 -有意思
So...
那么…
How can I help you?
有什么需要我帮忙的？
I have some questions about your son, Hayato Ippongi.
关于令郎一本木隼人 我有几个问题想问您
Do you know anybody who might hold a grudge against him?
您知道他是否有什么仇家吗？
Everyone despises my son.
所有人都看不起我儿子
Do you understand the weight
你懂得身为“被选中的人”
of being chosen?
要背负多少重担吗？
Everyone is
每个人生来
chosen for a role.
都被赋予了一个角色
Fulfilling that role
承担你的角色
can be very dangerous.
有时候是很危险的
That's why
所以
I didn't want to burden my son with such a heavy responsibility.
我原本不想把如此沉重的责任 压在我儿子的肩上
What do you mean by "dangerous"?
您说的“危险”是指什么？
Are you okay, sir?
您还好吗 先生？
I'm Sakon Renjo, the legal advisor.
我是公司的法律顾问 连城左近
Inukai.
我叫犬饲
The president has been sick for several years.
社长已经病了好几年了
On top of that,
雪上加霜的是
he's suffering from mental illness due to his son's situation.
由于他儿子的悲剧 他最近精神也出了问题
Could you leave for today, please?
二位今天能先离开吗？
We'd like to ask him a bit more...
我们想再问他一些…
If you could send us a questionnaire, we'll answer it.
请你们把想问的以书面形式发来 我们一定答疑解惑
By the way, is the chief doing well?
对了 你们的局长最近好吗？
We were classmates in college.
我和他是大学同学
Sorry for taking up your time.
抱歉占用您的时间了
Goodbye.
再见
One more question.
我还有最后一个问题
Do you know a college student named Kouki Shikazono?
您认识一个叫鹿苑科希的大学生吗？
I don't know.
我不认识
He was interning here.
他曾在这里实习
Do you know if there was any interaction between him and Hayato?
您知道他和隼人之间 是否有什么交集吗？
Who knows? He was just an intern.
这种事谁知道？ 毕竟他只是一个实习生
If we find out something, we'll let you know.
如果我们查到了什么 我们会告知警方的
Please do.
请务必这么做
Wait.
等一下
What does this look like to you?
你觉得这看起来像什么？
It depicts an animal that will eventually disappear.
这幅图画的是一种终将消亡的动物
Human beings.
人类
That was crazy.
刚才真是不可思议
You got a leaf.
你头发上沾了片树叶
You got one, too, Hachi.
你头发上也有 八公
Thanks.
谢谢你
You scared me!
你吓死我了！
Sorry to disturb you.
抱歉打扰到你们了
Oh, no, we were just taking a walk.
您误会了 我们只是在散步
Haven't you forgotten something?
你是不是忘了什么？
I was young once, too.
我也曾经年轻过
I'm sorry. Please excuse us.
抱歉 我们得先失陪了
Our waterfall is said to bring good luck.
据说我们的瀑布能带来好运哦
You seem to have found out about this special power.
看来你们已经发现了这股特别的魔力
This place is special. The spring, fireflies,
这里确实很特别 那泉水、萤火虫
and the intimacy with Hachi.
还有和八公的鱼水之…
I'm sorry. We're really going home now.
不好意思 我们真的要回家了
We are surrounded by a mysterious power.
我们被一种神秘的魔力围绕着
You could say this whole town is built on magic.
可以说 这整座镇子 都是以魔法建成的
Come back anytime.
欢迎你们随时回来
I'm always here.
我一直在这里
Strange guy.
那家伙真奇怪
Super awkward.
超尴尬的
Hachi, do you remember rule one?
八公 你还记得第一条规则吗？
What?
嗯？
Well, it seems like you won't be found here, at least.
至少住在这里 你就不会被发现了
If you need anything else, let me know.
如果你有任何需要 一定要告诉我
I sent you my Amazon wish list.
我把我的亚马逊愿望清单发给你了
A massage chair?
按摩椅？
It's apparently a magical chair that can relieve fatigue.
据说那是能够消除疲惫的神奇椅子
I desire it.
我很想要
You've really mastered this thing.
你完全把手机玩转了啊
Izzy, about rule three...
伊姬 关于第三条规则…
It's not easy.
那不是易事
Why?
为什么？
It's not that difficult to not kill people.
不杀人没那么难吧？
I don't kill people every day.
我每天都不杀人啊
If there's a reason, tell me.
如果有什么必须杀人的理由 告诉我
Long ago, humans and Yokai respected and supported each other,
很久以前 人类和妖怪尊重并支持彼此
leading peaceful lives,
过着平静的生活
until humans betrayed us.
直到人类背叛了我们
The war began,
战争爆发
and humans tried to eliminate us.
人类想将我们一族彻底消灭
Our brethren were killed one by one.
我们的同族被一个接一个杀死
My mother as well.
我母亲也未能幸免于难
Eventually, five powerful clans united,
最终 五个强大的人类家族联合起来
burying Yokai in the world between the afterlife
将妖怪封印在阴间
and this world, the World of Nothing.
和人世的交界处 “虚无世界”
We were exiled to the timeless darkness.
我们被放逐至永恒的黑暗中
I spent 500 years there.
我被困在那里500年
Each of the five powerful clans
五大家族中 每一族
has a guardian who sets up a barrier.
各有一位设置结界的守护者
I must find and bury the guardians
我必须找到所有守护者 将他们尽数杀死
and unravel the curses.
才能解开诅咒
You're the one who rescued me from the inferno, Hachi.
是你将我从地狱中救了出来 八公
I must lift the seal for the sake of my comrades.
而我必须解除封印 把我的族人解救出来
In other words, rule three is the reason you exist in this world, right?
也就是说 第三条规则 正是你存在的原因 对吧？
Can't we resolve this by talking?
我们不能通过谈判解决这件事吗？
To release my comrades,
要想释放我的族人
I need the heads of the remaining four Guardians.
我必须集齐其他四位守护者的头颅
Looking at it positively,
从积极的一面看
two out of the three rules are agreed upon.
至少三条规则中 我们就两条达成了一致
That's progress, isn't it?
这就算进步 对吧？
-Good morning.
-早上好
SAKON RENJO ATTORNEY
律师 连城左近
Something stinks.
有种奇怪的味道
Man, the police have no manners.
老天爷 那些警察还真是蛮不讲理
Now, what should I do?
接下来我该怎么做？